创世之初 冥冥之中
In the beginning, there was darkness...
随着轰的一声
and then, bang...
诞生了无限膨胀的
giving birth to an endless expanding existence...
时间 空间和物质
of time, space, and matter.
现在 所见超乎我们的想象
Now, see further than we've ever imagined...
超越了我们生存的限制
beyond the limits of our existence...
这个空间我们称之为"宇宙"
in a place we call "The Universe."
在太空里 威胁可以来自四面八方:
In space, threats can come from any direction:
来自深太空的陨石
meteors from deep space...
来自太阳的无形但致命的辐射爆
invisible but deadly bursts of radiation from the Sun...
其它星球上的山崩地裂
otherworldly landslides from above and Marsquakes from below.
外太空是你作为人类最不想去的地方
Outer space is the last place you want to be as a human being.
轨道上什么样的子弹比地球上更加致命?
What makes fire more deadly in orbit than on Earth?
人类暴露在...
What happens to someone...
极端恶劣的外太空里有什么后果?
exposed to the harsh extremes of outer space?
唾液 血液 会从液态变为气态
The saliva, the blood, goes from a liquid state...to a gaseous state.
系上安全带 准备应对《太空灾难》
Buckle up and prepare for "Space Disasters."
宇宙:太空灾难
2030年
The year is 2030.
一群宇航员
A crew of astronauts...
按下了太空电梯的上行按钮
simply hits the "up" button in a space elevator.
电梯将带他们登上飞船
The elevator will bring them to their spacecraft...
飞船已经在轨道上等候着他们
which will meet them in orbit.
他们庆幸自己
They're grateful they don't have to risk...
不必冒火箭升空爆炸的危险
the controlled explosion of a rocket launch.
我们现在已经能创造出碳纳米管纤维
We can now create carbon nanotube fibers...
其强度超过了钢铁
that are stronger than steel.
信不信由你 它们的强度足以
And believe it or not, they are strong enough...
让太空电梯漂浮在太空中
to keep a space elevator afloat in space...
这样你就能够一路攀升上天
so that you can literally climb your way into the heavens.
6万英里缆绳固定住空间站
The 60,000-mile cable is attached to the docking station...
它的运转速度与地球同步
that revolves at the same rate as the Earth.
类似于地球同步卫星
Just like a geosynchronous satellite...
它停留在地面固定一点的上方
it stays over a fixed spot on the ground.
太空电梯是所有宇航员梦寐以求的
A space elevator would be any astronaut's dream.
然而太空电梯之梦
But the space elevator dream...
同样也会变成一场噩梦
can also turn into a nightmare.
太空电梯必须固定在地球上
The space elevator has to be anchored to the Earth.
但是如果遇上风暴会有什么后果
But what happens if we have storms...
突然之间 锚具开始扯断
and, all of a sudden, the moorings begin to snap?
由于缆绳仍然固定在太空中
With the cable still attached up in space...
它就会开始疯狂摆动
it will start swinging wildly...
任意击打着数百英里外的物体
striking objects hundreds of miles away in any direction.
也有可能 某些导航计算机
It's also possible that some type of guidance computer...
或推进器产生的问题会敲打偏离航向的太空平台
or thruster problem could knock the platform in space off-course...
在顶部扯断缆绳
snapping the cable at the top.
如果此时正好有船员沿着缆绳上下
lf it happened while a crew was going up or down the cable...
那么他们就必定会遭遇生命中最后一次搭乘
they would be in for the last ride of their lives.
6万英里缆绳 砸向地球
And the 60,000 miles of cable, hurtling toward Earth...
其长度足以缠绕地球
is long enough to wrap itself around the planet...
几乎是赤道的3倍 造成大面积的破坏
almost three times at the equator, creating havoc over a wide area.
这不仅会对人类造成灾祸
It would be not only disastrous and dangerous...for the people involved...
而且 那样的东西所带来的动能
the kinetic energy of something like that...
会鞭击大气层 给航行带来威胁
whipping through the atmosphere, would be a menace to navigation...
所以它会对于其中所有的人类系统
so it's going to have an inherent danger in it...
带来潜在的危险
that any human system has.
这只是未来太空探险家所面对的N多
This is just one of many potential disasters...
潜在灾难之一
facing future space explorers.
定居在太空中也会涉及巨大的危险
Living in space will also involve grave dangers.
月球或火星上的移民
Colonies on the Moon or Mars...
所面临的威胁来自四面八方
will be faced with threats from all directions...
尤其是头顶上
especially above...
突然爆发的辐射高峰会致人于死地
where sudden spikes of radiation can turn deadly.
如果我们漫步在月球表面
If we were walking around on the surface of the Moon...
我想说我们的头号烦恼就是太阳耀斑
I would say our number one concern should be solar flare.
太阳爆发
The Sun erupts.
耀斑射出的质子会让宇航员送命
The protons coming from that flare could kill an astronaut.
最近20年里有过几次耀斑
There have been several flares over the last couple decades...
其中 假如我们有宇航员呆在月球上
which, if we had had astronauts on the Moon...
穿着宇航服四处活动 就会将他们置于死地
just walking around in a spacesuit, would have been lethal for them.
在地球上 我们躲过了多数辐射
On Earth, we're protected from most radiation.
地球的大气层和磁场 就像是保护盾
Earth's atmosphere and magnetic field are like a protective fence...
只让少量的粒子通过
letting only a fraction of particles through.
而在月球或火星上 你就直接处在了一线
On the Moon and Mars, you are directly in the firing line.
月球没有大气层或磁场
The Moon has no atmosphere or magnetic field.
火星只有很少的大气
Mars has very little atmosphere...
以及很弱的局部磁场
and only weak, localized magnetic fields.
航天局认为太阳耀斑的威胁非同小可
NASA takes the solar flare threat seriously...
因为它差一点害死阿波罗宇航员
because it has already come close to killing Apollo astronauts.
阿波罗登月宇航员相当幸运
The Apollo lunar landing crews were quite fortunate.
1972年8月 有一次严重的太阳耀斑
In 1972, in August, there was a major solar flare.
他们称之为大太阳风暴的耀斑
There was what they call the Great Solar Storm...
恰好就发生在了
that happened to just take place...
那年4月的阿波罗16号任务与
in between the Apollo 16 mission in April...
12月的阿波罗17号任务之间
and the Apollo 17 mission in December of that year.
要是此时有宇航员呆在月球上
Had that occurred while there was a crew...
早已经不在人世了
on the surface of the Moon, they would have been dead.
其结局就会像那些在
The effects would be similar to certain people...
广岛和长崎罹难的人...
who died in Hiroshima and Nagasaki...
他们并未命丧最初的爆炸
those who were not killed in the initial blast...
而是在几秒钟之内被致命的
but were overwhelmed by the extreme radiation dosage...
辐射剂量所击倒
within several seconds.
遭遇那种状况的宇航员几乎没有时间作出反应
An astronaut caught in that situation will have little time to react.
致命的粒子流穿透身体
A flood of deadly particles penetrates the body...
瞬间杀死宇航员的所有的细胞
killing all of the astronaut's cells in a few brief moments.
所以不足为奇的是太空移民
So it's no surprise that space colonists...
必须时刻保持警惕
will need to be constantly on alert.
我们需要天气预报
We're going to need weather reports...
但是他们需要的是太空天气预报
but they're going to be space weather reports.
我们需要有卫星来监视太阳
We're going to need satellites monitoring the Sun...
让我们得到耀斑的预警
giving us advance warning of flares.
太阳发出的光只要8分钟就抵达月球了
The light from the Sun takes only eight minutes to reach the Moon.
随之而来的是粒子
Coming behind it would be the particles...
致命的辐射
the lethal radiation.
你会有几分钟 半个小时 争分夺秒
You'd have minutes, half an hour, that sort of time frame...
寻找庇护之地
before you wanted to really be in a shelter.
这样的风暴可能会持续几天
Such a storm might last for a couple of days.
一个保护办法就是居住在地下
One option for protection is living underground.
但是别让荒芜的地形蒙骗了你
But don't let the barren terrain fool you.
月球和火星依然是活跃的天体
The Moon and Mars are still active bodies...
地球上能见到的自然灾害会时有发生
where natural disasters like those seen on Earth can strike.
我现在来是在莫哈韦沙漠中的一个熔岩流创造的岩洞里
I'm here in the Mojave Desert in a cave created by a lava flow...
上面是5到6英尺高的岩石
underneath five or six feet of rocks.
呆在地下岩洞里可能是定居月球
Well, being underground in a cave may be an option for habitation...
或火星的一个选择
on the Moon or on Mars.
在月球或火星表面
On the surface of the Moon and Mars...
存在着太阳辐射 存在着宇宙辐射
there's radiation from the Sun, there's cosmic radiation.
火星上 还有尘埃暴
On Mars, there's dust storms.
如果我们呆在地下 可以避开那些危害
lf we're underground, we're safe from those hazards...
但是还有其它的危害
but we have other hazards.
想象一下 在这个岩洞里 一旦发生地震
Imagine being in this cave when there's quakes...
岩石滚落 会砸中我们 压住我们
rocks falling down, crushing us, pinning us.
月球或火星的星震
A Moon or Marsquake...
同样会威胁到地面上的移民
could also threaten an aboveground colony.
月球和火星没有板块
The Moon and Mars don't have tectonic plates...
类似于引发地球大部分地震和火山
like the ones that cause most of Earth's quakes...
喷发的板块
and volcanic eruptions.
没有活火山的迹象
And there are no signs of active volcanoes.
但是月球和火星同样有炙热的星核
But the Moon and Mars do have hot cores.
所以在热产生的对地表的压力作用下 就会产生震颤
So as the pressure from that heat heads to the surface, the shaking starts.
一旦发生星震 通常还会有另一个灾害
And where there's quakes, there's often another disaster.
就在不久前 我们看到了火星上的山崩
Just recently, we've seen a landslide occurring on Mars.
那是在轨摄像机所拍到的
It was captured with the cameras in orbit.
因此我们知道这个确实发生了
So we know this does happen...
很难被发现
and that can be hard to predict.
我们可以将基地建在某些地方
We might put our base someplace...
那里貌似万无一失
which appears perfectly safe...
然后 几年后
and then, a few years later...
就会了解到存在着滑坡的危害
realize that there's a landslide hazard.
科学家尚无法肯定200年发生在
Scientists are still unsure what started the 2008 landslide...
火星北极附近的滑坡
near the north pole of Mars.
那里是个冰冻的地区
It was in an icy area...
研究人员认为大部分滑坡物质是冰
and researchers believe most of the slide material was ice.
那类地形就是潜在的殖民地
That's just the type of place a colony might be located...
以利用冰转变成饮用水
to take advantage of converting the ice to drinkable water.
即使是遥远的星震也会触发殖民地周边的滑坡
Even a distant quake could still trigger a slide near a colony.
要是有条隐蔽的断层正好就在建筑下方有如何呢?
But what if a hidden fault line is running right under the buildings?
将来 空间移民定居月球或火星
In the future, space colonists living on the Moon or Mars...
将会面对大量的威胁
will have plenty of threats to deal with...
包括月球和火星星震之类的自然灾害
including natural disasters like moonquakes and Marsquakes.
它们的活跃程度不如我们所呆的地球
They're not active the way we're used to on Earth.
它们的活跃程度不同
They're active in different ways...
程度有可能出人意料
and there may be unexpected ways...
它们有可能对我们造成问题
that they could cause problems for us.
由于我们当前对这些世界的认识
Since our current knowledge of these other worlds...
实际上只是涉及了皮毛
has literally only scratched the surface...
有可能在将来
it's possible that in the future...
我们有可能就在断层上建立基地
we could locate a base right over a fault line...
而没有意识到下面的情况
without realizing what's below.
因为在携带东西上太空时
And since weight is always an issue...
重量一直是个问题
when carrying things into space...
所以较轻的建筑可能会相当脆弱
the lightweight buildings could be quite vulnerable...
尤其是外层
especially the outer layer.
万一保护层有什么意外
lf anything happens to that protective layer...
那就会有麻烦 措手不及的麻烦
that's trouble, very rapid trouble.
由于空气流出定居点
As the gases stream out of the habitat...
你就必须有一个非常有效和快速的程序
you've got to have a very efficient and quick procedure...
穿上宇航服以求生存 这就是失压
for getting into a spacesuit to survive that sort of decompression.
死神不会马上降临
Death would not be instantaneous...
一旦殖民地里的氧气及气压突然丧失的话
if oxygen and atmospheric pressure inside the colony are suddenly lost.
火星上 存在着稀薄的空气
On Mars, there is a thin atmosphere...
但是无法吸入 因为几乎全是二氧化碳
although it's not breathable since it's mostly carbon dioxide.
在月球上 就只是真空地带
On the Moon, there is only the vacuum of space.
不过你仍有机会
But you'd still have a chance...
因为我们已经从地球上的真空室里的
as we've learned from industrial accidents...
安全事故中有所认识
in vacuum chambers on Earth.
反映出生存能力约在一分钟左右
Exposure for maybe a minute or so is survivable.
如果你呆在真空中时间够长
Now, if you stay in a vacuum long enough...
又没有足够的氧气
there's not enough oxygen...
那么你血液和组织里的饱和氮
so nitrogen that's saturated in your blood and your tissues...
会溶解 产生泡沫
comes out of solution and causes bubbles.
那就是减压症
That's decompression sickness.
此外 你假如屏住呼吸
And also, if you hold your breath...
就会患上所谓的肺气肿
you can get what they call pulmonary overinflation...
你的肺就会破裂进你的血液系统
and your lung ruptures into your bloodstream...
形成所谓的血栓
and that's called an embolism.
因而暴露在真空中
So there's multiple factors that can result in death...
有多种因素会导致死亡
from exposure to the vacuum of space.
其次还有极端的温度
Then there's the temperature extremes.
月球上的温度
Temperatures on the Moon...
会从高达240华氏度
go from a high of about 240 degrees Fahrenheit...
降到华氏负290度
down to around 290 below.
火星同样这么寒冷
Mars can get just as cold...
尽管你可能会幸运地碰上
although you could get lucky...
舒适的70度的夏季
and have a nice 70-degree summer day.
但是没有可呼吸的大气
But without a breathable atmosphere...
户外不穿宇航服可是个非常糟糕的想法
going outside without a spacesuit is still a very bad idea.
另一方面 太空移民...
Another thing aboveground space colonists...
必须重点关注的...
will have to be on the lookout for...
就是陨石
is meteors.
月球上的环形山一诉衷肠
The craters on the Moon tell the story.
它是攻击的目标
It's an easy target.
我们这里相对比较安逸
We're relatively comfortable down here...
置身于层层保护之下
underneath these layers of protection.
我们有厚厚的大气层
We've got a thick atmosphere...
吸收并烧掉了陨石
which absorbs and burns up meteorites.
你到了月球 就完全不同了
You go to the Moon, nothing.
那里没有稠密的大气
There's no thick atmosphere.
我们所遭遇的一切就是你必须接受的空间
We are exposed to everything that space is throwing at us.
如果我们去火星 那里有稀薄的空气
If we go to Mars, there's a thin atmosphere...
但是一点都不如地球
but it's not anywhere near as good as the Earth's.
再说 我们会遭遇到太空闯入的东西
Again, we're exposed to what's coming in from space.
较小的陨石只有几英寸甚至一英寸大
Smaller meteors that are only inches or fractions of an inch wide...
叫做微流星体
known as micrometeoroids...
会打击频繁 毫无先兆
will strike most often and without warning.
你漫游在火星表面
You're walking along the surface of Mars...
会有沙粒般是大小的东西
then something the size of a grain of sand...
射入你的宇航服
comes slamming into your spacesuit.
那将是个非同小可的问题
That's going to be a serious problem.
将会使宇航服失压
It's going to be a loss of the pressure in the spacesuit.
这就意味着可以夺走宇航员的生命
It could mean loss of life of an astronaut.
只要我们有许多人在其它世界里开展大量的活动
When we have lots of people doing a lot of work on other worlds...
免不了会发生那样的事情
eventually that's going to happen.
那相当于雷击
That's the equivalent of a lightning strike...
虽然罕见 但有可能是致命的
a rare, possibly fatal event.
微流星体还可能洞穿
Micrometeoroids could also punch a hole...
定居点建筑的墙体
through the wall of a colony building.
类似于空间站 定居点可能是由
Like space stations, colonies will probably be built...
一系列的单元和舱位构建的
in a series of sections or modules.
就像宇航员在紧急情况下 不得不关闭空间站的舱位一样
And just as crews have had to seal off sections...
移民也有可能这么做
of a space station in an emergency, colonists will likely do the same.
较大的陨石有望被跟踪到
Large meteors will hopefully be tracked...
因此移民们会知晓它们的动向
so the colonists will know they're coming.
然而撤离有可能适得其反
But evacuation might not do any good.
不远处的打击依然会掀起数英里的致命的冲击波
A nearby strike would still send out a deadly shockwave for miles.
10英尺大的陨石撞击具有
A 10-foot wide meteor hits with the explosive equivalent...
6000到8000吨的爆炸当量
of 6,000 to 8,000 tons of TNT.
溅起的碎片也会损坏定居点建筑 无法修复
Flying debris could also damage colony buildings beyond repair.
靠近命中点的所有东西
And anything approaching a direct hit...
将会荡然无存
there'll be little evidence that the colonists were ever there.
移民不可能选择
It's unlikely that colonists...
居住在火星的火山附近
would live anywhere near one of Mars' volcanoes.
月球在最近几十亿年里
And the Moon probably hasn't seen volcanic activity...
尚未见到过有火山活动
in the last few billion years.
但是即使是古代火山的遗迹
But even ancient remnants of volcanoes...
依然会给车子里的宇航员造成麻烦
could still cause trouble for crews in vehicles.
月球和火星都显示出火山熔岩流的痕迹
Both the Moon and Mars show evidence of volcanic flows.
因此我们有望找到这种东西
So we might expect to find there this sort of thing...
火山洞穴
volcanic caves.
设想一下在其表面驱车行进
Imagine driving along the surface.
遇上其中的一个 你是避之不及的
Come across one of these, you're not expecting it...
它会毁了你一天 会毁了你的车子
that could ruin your day. It could ruin your vehicle.
你会掉入坑底无法脱身
You could be at the bottom of this pit without any way to get up.
更为糟糕的是想象一下有火山岩洞
Even worse would be imagining one of these volcanic caves...
上面只有薄薄的一层火山岩
with a thin layer of volcanic rock on top of it.
你在其顶上越过 就会让你跌入深渊
You move across on top of that, it gives, and down you go.
但是并非所有的殖民地灾难都是如此戏剧性的
But not all colony disasters will be so dramatic.
哪怕耗尽补给就是最大的危险之一
Simply running out of supplies is one of the greatest dangers.
由于月球近得多
Since the Moon is much closer...
紧急救援物资能够在几天内送达
emergency supplies could arrive in a matter of days.
而对于火星 援助将要几个月乃至数年
With Mars, help is many months to years away...
这取决于行星的排列
depending on how the planets are aligned.
火星上 一旦出现问题 断了后勤
On Mars, if something goes wrong and you lose some supplies...
地球的补给可能要迟后2到3年
resupply from Earth can be two or three years away.
你以为你足以坚持到最后
You think you've got enough to last...
你意外地失去了一半 那你就完完了
you lose half of it to an accident, you're dead.
这是个现实问题
It's a real problem.
我认为这意味着你必须拥有的
I think that means you're going to have to have...
要大大超过你需要的
more than what you need.
你必须足以应付5到6年
You're going to have to have enough for five, six years.
生活在家门口的太空里
Living in space much closer to home...
太空站里和航天飞机里
on space stations and longer shuttle flights...
都已经让我们看到了太空中的危险了
has already taught us a lot about the dangers of space.
火灾是宇航员的头号杀手
And fire is space crew enemy number one.
火灾威胁巨大的原因就在于传统的航天器里
The reason fire is such a threat is because spacecraft traditionally...
氧气的水平高于大气层
have higher levels of oxygen than the atmosphere...
当然在压力下其含量更高
certainly in higher concentrations under pressure.
其中遍布各种电子设备
They are also filled with electronic equipment.
电子设备会发热 往往会产生火花和电弧
Electronic equipment puts out heat, and often there are sparks and arcs.
这是个糟糕的组合
It's a bad combination.
庆幸的是 设计师已经让航天员扑火更加便捷
Luckily, designers have made it easier for crews to put out fires...
所有的数英里电线都隐蔽在控制面板的背后
where all those miles of wire lurk behind the control panels.
这是航天飞机驾驶舱的样机
This is a mockup of the space shuttle flight deck...
我们用来训练宇航员
that we use for training of crews.
如果你注意这里的各种面板
If you look at the various panels we have...
你就会发现四周布满了这样的小孔
you will see small holes like this at various locations around it.
这些是为灭火器设计的
And these are for fire extinguishers...
因此一旦有面板背后发生火灾
so that if there is a fire behind one of these panels...
你就可以将灭火器对准灭火
you can put an extinguisher in there to extinguish the fire.
安德鲁.托马斯对太空中的火灾有所了解
Andrew Thomas knows a thing or two about fires in space.
1998年在和平号空间站里 一场火灾突然爆发
While on the Mir Space Station in 1998, a fire suddenly broke out.
所有的烟雾被抽进了隔间
All the smoke was pumped right out into the cabin.
航天员冲过密封舱
Crews hurtle through space in their enclosed craft...
拼命保住里面的地球一样的大气
desperate to maintain the Earth-like atmosphere inside.
到了这里 火灾是最大的威胁之一
Out here, fire is one of the biggest threats.
1988年 航天局的安德鲁.托马斯
In 1998, NASA astronaut Andrew Thomas...
和两名俄罗斯宇航员一起登上了和平号空间站
is onboard the Mir Space Station with two Russian cosmonauts.
突然 发生了火灾
Suddenly, a fire breaks out.
讽刺的是 发生火灾时
Ironically, the fire starts...
正在清扫所谓的空气净化设备
while cleaning what's known as an air scrubber...
过滤器之一 目的是为了去除呼出的二氧化碳
one of the filters designed to remove exhaled carbon dioxide...
以及空间环境中的其它毒素
and other toxins from the space crew's environment.
所有的烟雾被抽进了隔间
All the smoke was pumped right out into the cabin.
突然之间 空间站一部分隔间
And so, all of a sudden, the cabin in one part of the space station...
马上充满了浓烟
just became thick with a pall of smoke.
当然啦 所有的空气处理器
And, of course, all the air handlers...
接着除去了飞船周围的烟雾
then moved all that smoke around the spacecraft...
这样在近两个小时里
so within about two hours...
整个飞船充满了烟雾
the entire spacecraft was completely filled with smoke.
因此我们只得等待空气处理器
So we had to just wait for the air handlers...
来清除整个污染
to scrub all of this contamination out.
花了约两天的时间
And that took about two days.
我们都反应出那种环境下的中毒
And we all manifested symptoms of the toxicity of that environment.
一旦大量的一氧化碳达到那样的等级
When there's a lot of carbon monoxide at those levels...
你就会恶心 犯糊涂
you have nausea, a certain amount of confusion...
头痛不已 因为你缺氧了
invariably a headache because you're oxygen-deprived.
就是一种非常不舒服的感觉
It's just a very uncomfortable feeling.
太空中的火灾危害
The dangers of fire in space...
远不止是你无法打开窗户
go beyond the fact that you can't open a window...
或呼叫911
or call the fire department.
火灾在失重的飞船里的表现完全不同
Fire actually behaves differently inside a spacecraft in zero gravity.
我们现在看到的是蜡烛火苗
What we are seeing is a candle flame.
下面的那个是正常重力下的蜡烛
The bottom one is a candle in normal gravity.
你可以看到火苗向上
As you can see the flame moves up because buoyancy...
因为浮力往上推动着火苗周围的热空气
pushes the hot gases around the flame up.
上面那张照片是同样的蜡烛
The top photograph is the same candle...
但是是在失重的情况下
but in the absence of gravity.
哥伦比亚Spacehab公司锁定了隔舱
Columbia SPACEHAB lock for the module.
燃烧会在15秒里从这里烧起
The Mist burn will be initiated here in about 15 seconds.
炙热的气体不会升起
The hot gases don't move up...
你见到的是个球形的火苗
and what you have is a spherical flame.
有一个火苗
There is the flame...
这就是燃烧模组二的初始燃烧点
so here's the initial light off for Combustion Module Two.
在顶棚上安上烟雾探测器 像在地球上一样
So putting a smoke detector on the ceiling like we do on Earth...
在太空中是不起作用的
doesn't work in space.
相反 探测器要靠近小抽吸设备
Instead, detectors are located next to small suction devices...
那会将空气 烟雾及其它毒素抽向探测器
that draw air and any smoke or other toxins toward the detector.
为了弄明白太空中的火灾有多危险
To figure out just how dangerous fire is in space...
费尔南德斯.佩略教授的团队在
Professor Fernandez-Pello's team performs experiments...
加州大学伯克利分校的燃烧实验室里开展了实验
in the University of California, Berkeley, combustion lab...
利用KC 135飞机短暂的零重力
and on KC-135 aircraft in short bursts of zero g.
理论上 零重力下的火灾应该不会很剧烈
In theory, fires in zero gravity should be less intense...
因为热空气不会上升
because the hot gases don't rise...
这就意味着冷空气不会从下面吸入
which means cool air isn't drawn in at the base...
来补充给火焰
to keep feeding the flames.
但是他们发现实际上飞船里面更加危险
But they're finding that the reality inside a spacecraft is more dangerous.
空调系统会创造出小小的气流
Air conditioning systems create small air currents.
那些气流会带来新鲜空气 或者说是 火上加油
Those currents bring fresh air or, in this case, fuel to the fire.
同时 低气流和失重
At the same time, the low airflow and lack of gravity...
并不会像在地球上那样快速散热
don't remove the heat as quickly as on Earth.
结果是..
The result...
此类火灾要比正常重力下温度更高
These type of fires are hotter and more dangerous...
更加危险
than in normal gravity.
火灾可能成为了不容忽视的安全问题
And fire is likely to become even more of a safety hazard...
对于新设计的
inside the new Aries/Orion spacecraft...
替代航天飞机的白羊座/猎户座飞船
being designed to replace the shuttle.
他们已经决定要做的
What they've decided to do...
就是减少压力 增加氧气
was to reduce the pressure and increase the oxygen.
这样做后 他们可以减少准备时间
And by doing this, they reduced the preparation time...
让宇航员
that it takes for the astronauts...
从舱内跑到舱外
to go from the vehicle to outside of the vehicle.
所以我们所干的就是测试
So what we're doing is we're testing materials...
打算用在那种环境中的材料
at that proposed environment.
我们了解到了 对于他们所处的环境
We've learned that for the environment that they've chosen...
对于他们下一代的航天器
for their next generation of vehicles...
物体的实际燃烧
things actually ignite about 20 percent faster...
要比目前的环境快上二成
than they would in the current environment.
高氧含量和低气流的结合
The combination of high oxygen content and low airflow...
意味着几乎所有的东西都会着火 甚至金属
means just about anything can catch fire, even metal.
在最坏的未来场景中
In a worst-case future scenario...
空间站的航天员无法迅速扑灭火灾
a space station crew is unable to quickly extinguish a fire.
它会在密封舱里快速蔓延
It grows too fast to seal off in a separate module.
即使他们戴上紧急氧气面罩
Even if they put on emergency oxygen masks...
炙热的火焰也有可能使其丧生
the heat of the flames will likely kill them.
即使他们有可能躲过火焰
And if they're somehow able to survive the flames...
过滤系统也完全有可能超载
the filtering system is completely overloaded.
他们会在烟雾的熏烤中慢慢死去
They are left to die in a toxic stew from smoke inhalation.
在失控的火灾中幸存的最佳机会
The best chance of survival with an out-of-control fire...
就是弃船 回到返回舱
is to abandon ship and return in a re-entry capsule...
如果有的话
if one is available.
那就是阿波罗13号宇航员存活的关键
That was the key to the survival of the crew of Apollo 13.
1970年4月11日
April 11, 1970.
三名宇航员进入太空
The three-man crew launches into space.
两天后 在他们去月球的途中
Two days later, on their way to the Moon...
一个氧气罐突然爆炸了
an oxygen tank suddenly explodes.
爆炸造成了氧气的大量流失
The explosion causes a substantial loss of oxygen...
危及到了服务舱的电力系统
and damages the Service Module's electrical system.
船员们被迫挤在狭窄的登月舱里
The crew is forced to live in the cramped lunar capsule.
阿波罗13就是一个失败但无伤亡的典型案例
Apollo 13 is the classic case of the failure that doesn't kill you.
它撞上了合适的时间
It happened at the right time.
它发生在了他们去月球的途中
It happened when they were on their way to the Moon...
因此他们可以将登月舱用作救生舱
so they could use the Lunar Module as a lifeboat...
回到了地球
and get back to Earth.
如果同样的问题发生在登月后
Had the same problem occurred after the lunar landing...
洛弗尔 格特 海瑟返回地球途中
when Lovell, Swigert, and Haise were on their way back to Earth...
那就会束手无策了
there would've been nothing they could do.
他们就不会生还了
They would've been dead.
火灾威胁在宇航服里尤为突出
The threat of fire is especially high inside spacesuits.
太空行走 又称EVAs
During spacewalks, also known as EVAs...
即舱外活动...
or extra-vehicular activity...
太空服需要保持较低的压力
the spacesuits need to be kept at low pressures.
作业于地球大气层里
Working at a fraction of Earth's atmosphere...
关键在于灵活
is the key to flexibility.
如果你穿的宇航服有一个大气压
If you had a spacesuit that was at one atmosphere...
你就会基本上像一只气球
you would be like, basically, in a balloon...
无法动弹
and you couldn't move.
由于低气压 就像是
With low pressure, just like a climber...
珠峰稀薄空气中的登山者
in the thin atmosphere of Mount Everest...
宇航员需要吸入高燃度的纯氧
astronauts need to breathe highly flammable 100 percent oxygen.
这是宇航服的手臂
This is an arm from the spacesuit.
它焚毁于1980年约翰逊航天中心的一场大火
It was burned up in a fire in 1980 at Johnson Space Center...
那只是一些检查测试
just doing some checkout tests...
加压系统带有两个不同氧源
pressurizing the system with the two different oxygen sources...
大火发生时 要知道 相当震惊
and when this fire occurred, it was, you know, quite a shock.
大家就站在它旁边
People were standing nearby it...
曾以为有人会穿上宇航服在第二天
and someone was supposed to be in the suit the next day...
进行载人测试
for a manned test.
它经受住了致命的大火
And it could've been a fatal fire.
即使这样 这套服装在当时还是价值310万美元
Even as it is, this suit is worth, at the time, $3.1 million.
它还花了航天局2000万美元从这场大火中复原
And it also took NASA $20 million to recover from this fire...
目的是为了重新设计服装
in terms of redesigning the suit.
舱外活动还有其它危险因素
Extra-vehicular activity is dangerous for many other reasons as well.
事实上 世界上首次太空行走几乎终结于灾难
In fact, the world's first spacewalk almost ended in disaster.
阿列克谢.列昂诺夫在1965年
Alexei Leonov did the first spacewalk...
进行了史无前例的首次太空行走
that any human did in 1965.
但是在匆忙完成那个空间壮举
But in the rush to accomplish that space spectacular...
从而击败老美的过程中
and thereby beat the Americans...
苏联人对宇航员的安全走了一些捷径
the Soviets took some shortcuts on the safety of the cosmonaut...
所以他就像是个充足气的米其林人
and so he blew up like the Michelin Man.
太空服变得很僵硬
The suit became rigid.
它无法处理里面的可呼吸的大气和
It couldn't handle the pressure differences...
真空之间的压差
between the breathable atmosphere inside and the vacuum of space.
问题在于 你登上了飞船
The problem is, is you've got a spacecraft...
联盟号密封舱是很小的
in the Soyuz capsule that he was flying, that's very small...
其舱口还要非常小
and the hatch for it is even smaller.
最后 他的反应就是放掉一点气了
Ultimately, his response was to let a little bit of the air out...
把东西缩到足够小
and just deflate the thing enough...
这样就能够爬行通过舱口
so that he can crawl back in through the hatch.
然而他会告诉你 那天
But he will tell you that to this day...
他无法肯定他能否做到
that he wasn't sure he'd be able to make it.
一个宇航员 比如列昂诺夫 不得不减小压力
An astronaut having, like Leonov, to let the pressure out...
为了在里头能够机动 其情况类似于
in order to be able to maneuver in it is in the same situation...
潜水员快速从深水区升上来
as a diver ascending from deep water too quickly.
氮气泡会在你的血液里形成
Nitrogen bubbles will form in your bloodstream...
不光是痛苦 它们还会夺走你的生命
and not only be painful, they'll kill you.
在舱外 一个看似简单的事情 诸如未扣紧绳子
And during EVAs, a simple thing, such as an unsecured tether...
或紧急推进器未点火 都会导致灾难
or a misfiring emergency thruster, can also spell disaster.
在航天器外进行漫步
Being outside of a spacecraft on a spacewalk...
是宇航员在轨道上做的最危险的事情
is the most dangerous thing an astronaut in orbit can do.
走错一步就会送命
One false move can be deadly...
尤其是错误的一步让你远离了飞船
especially if that false move takes you away from the spacecraft.
这里有个例子
There was an instance...
在俄罗斯的空间站礼炮号上
on one of the Russian space stations, the Salyut...
有一个航天员未被拴住
where one of the crew members was not tethered...
他在气闸区里观察其他成员
and he was in the airlock area, watching the other crew member...
他缓慢地漂移出去
and he slowly started to drift out...
其他宇航员看到后 赶紧抓住了他
and the other cosmonaut saw him and grabbed him.
太空中无拘无束的人
An untethered person in space...
没有适当的推进系统来返回
without appropriate propulsion system to get back...
将是极其危险的
would be very, very serious.
我的意思是 基本上你会失踪的
I mean, basically, you're lost at sea.
即使有推进系统 它也可能失败
Even with a propulsion system, it can fail...
或耗尽有限的推进燃料
or run out of its limited propellant supply...
而宇航员还未抵达安全地带
before the astronaut reaches safety.
宇航员在太空中只会飘起来
The astronaut will simply keep floating off into space.
国际空间站是无法相互追逐的
The International Space Station is unable to chase someone down.
如果航天飞机对接
And if the shuttle were docked...
需要很长时间来驶离和组织营救
it would take too long to undock and mount a rescue.
在这种噩梦里
In this nightmare scenario...
宇航员有可能只剩余几个小时的氧气供应
the astronaut will likely have several hours of oxygen remaining...
来坚持到最后
to contemplate the end.
只要航天服完好无损 压力不是个问题
As long as the suit is intact, pressure will not be an issue.
要么是氧气耗尽
Either the oxygen will run out...
要么是系统 排除呼出的二氧化碳
or the system, which removes exhaled carbon dioxide...
停止了工作
will stop working.
无论什么 宇航员都会窒息而亡
Either way, the astronaut will suffocate...
永远漂浮在虚无的太空中
and continue floating into the emptiness of space.
微流星体 可以摧毁太空殖民地
The same micrometeoroids that can devastate space colonies...
同时也对太空行走乃至整个航天器
also pose a lethal threat to spacewalks...
构成了致命的威胁
and entire spacecraft.
此外 在低地球轨道上
Plus, in low-Earth orbit...
这些岩石小家伙有着自己的商号: 太空垃圾
these rocky little gremlins have company: space junk.
所有这些东西奔跑的速度
And all of these things are racing around...
超过了时速2.2万英里
at over 22,000 miles an hour.
在那样的速度下 只有一英寸大的东西
At these speeds, objects that are only a fraction of an inch wide...
都可能是致命的
can be deadly.
穿行太空的微流星体
A micrometeoroid flying through space...
很像是空中划过的高尔夫球
is a lot like a golf ball flying through the air...
具有以下差异:
with these differences:
微流星体要小得多
the micrometeoroid is much, much smaller.
因为它超高速飞行
And because it travels at hypervelocity...
在其撞击时破坏力极大
it's far more destructive when it hits.
一旦微流星体击中你的航天服
lf a micrometeoroid hits your spacesuit...
就会打出一个洞
it's going to put a hole in it.
你是无法修补的
You don't have reach or the ability to patch or fix it.
除非你旁边有个宇航员伙伴
Unless you've got a fellow astronaut right there...
否则你完蛋了
you're going to die.
你的空气将迅速泄漏光
Your air is going to leak out fairly quickly.
将会大量涌出
It's going to gush out.
你的血液会沸腾 就这么回事
Your blood's going to boil. That's going to be it.
是什么导致了血液沸腾?
And what causes blood to boil?
在太空中 血液沸腾与热量毫无关系
Well, in space, boiling blood has nothing to do with heat.
完全在于突然失压
It's all about the sudden lack of atmospheric pressure.
血液沸腾的说法其实属于用词不当
The idea that blood boils is really a misnomer.
你体内的液体
The liquid in your body...
会从液态变成气态
goes from a liquid state to a gaseous state.
有好多故事 说的是外太空中
There have been many tales about what happens...
未受保护之人的情况
to an unprotected person in outer space.
这是个真实的故事
Here's the real story.
由于太空的真空进入了太空行走者破损的服装
As the vacuum of space fills the spacewalker's leaking suit...
舌头和眼睛的液体部分开始起泡
the liquid parts of the tongue and eyes begin to bubble...
此外还有唾液 体液以及血液
along with all of the saliva, internal fluids, and blood.
由于血液转变成气体
As the blood turns to gas...
氧气不再输送到大脑和其它部位
oxygen no longer travels to the brain or anywhere else.
大脑在15秒里停止了工作
The brain shuts down within about 15 seconds...
使得受害者丧失了意志
leaving the victim unconscious.
很快 体内的其它细胞逐一死去
Soon after, the rest of the cells in the body die.
极端的温度同样也起了作用
Temperature extremes could also play a role...
由于阳光照射的地方温度高达华氏250度
since the sunlit areas of space reach 250 degrees Fahrenheit...
而背阴处温度骤降
and the shaded areas quickly plummet...
达到零下250度
to 250 degrees below zero.
多大的孔对于宇航服才算是大的呢?
And just how big a hole is too big for a spacesuit?
你其实问的是以很少量的材料
You're really asking a very small amount of material...
来阻止粒子以每秒7公里速度的侵入
to stop a particle that could be coming in at seven kilometers per second.
你可以从实验中看到入口
You can see the entry hole from the test...
它有好多层
and it has many, many layers...
最里面是所谓的内胆
ending with what's called the bladder...
这是承压层
and this is a pressure-retaining layer.
这是约2到3毫米的孔
That's about a two to three-millimeter hole.
4毫米对于柔软材料做的舱外服来说
A four-millimeter for an EVA suit in the soft goods, this material...
是灾难性的
would be considered catastrophic.
幸运的是 太空中尚无人遭遇到这样的厄运
Luckily, no one in space has ever suffered this fate.
撞击也会造成更为隐蔽的麻烦
Impacts can also cause trouble in sneakier ways.
因而航天局在地球上不遗余力地模拟
So NASA goes to great lengths to simulate different types...
微流星体的破坏
of micrometeoroid damage down on Earth.
新墨西哥州的白沙测试基地的
Researchers inside the Hypervelocity Building...
超高速大楼里的研究人员
of the White Sands test facility in New Mexico...
利用压缩氢气枪来制造撞击
create impacts using compressed hydrogen gas guns.
这些枪无疑会产生热量
These guns definitely bring the heat...
以时速1.9万英里将物体
shooting objects up to 19,000 miles per hour...
射向航天飞机以及空间站的部件 以评估其危害
at shuttle and space station parts to assess the damage.
以那样的速度 你从洛杉矶到纽约
At that velocity, you can get from Los Angeles to New York...
只要约8分钟
in about eight minutes.
我们今天所进行的测试
The testing that we're going to perform today...
是对一个国际空间站的把手
is on an International Space Station handle that the astronauts use...
那是宇航员在空间站外用的
on the outside of the space station...
目的是安全地横跨空间站
in order to transverse around the space station safely.
有几个宇航员已经被割破了手套
Several astronauts have cut their gloves severely.
这引起了航天局的高度关注
This is a great concern to NASA...
因为他们当时设计空间站时
because when they designed the space station...
他们非常仔细地去除了锋利的边缘
they are very careful to eliminate all sharp edges...
因为你不想看到有东西钩住
because you don't want something snagging...
宇航员的宇航服
the astronauts' spacesuits...
拉出口子 终止任务
and creating a hole and ending a mission.
技术人员在靶室里安装好把手
Technicians mount the handle in the target chamber...
在支座上放上1/32英寸大小的小弹丸
place the tiny 1/32-of-an-inch-wide projectile within a holder...
它会在发射后立马破碎
that will disintegrate once fired...
然后在枪膛里装上火药
then add gunpowder to the breech.
我们用火药来推动活塞
We take gunpowder and propel a piston...
以每平方英寸10磅的压力来压缩氢气
which compresses hydrogen gas up to about 100,000 PSI.
高压气体加速弹丸
It's that highly compressed gas that accelerates the projectiles...
从零加速到时速1.9万英里
from zero to 19,000 miles per hour.
我们用上了三种不同类型的相机
We use three different types of cameras.
一个是抓拍 另一个拍摄电影
One takes a snapshot, another one takes a film...
第三个是数码相机
and the third type is a digital camera...
以每秒2亿帧的速度拍摄16帧画面
which takes 16 frames at 200 million frames per second.
技术员撤除了背后防爆罩
The technicians retreat behind a blast shield...
准备发射
and prepare to fire.
舱体里已经抽去了氧气和其他气体
The chamber is cleared of oxygen and other gases...
以模拟外太空的真空
to simulate the vacuum of outer space.
现在见真章了
Now the moment of truth.
这个模拟微流星体究竟会造成多大的危害呢?
How much damage did this simulated micrometeoroid cause?
即使是个很小的撞击
Even though it is a small impact...
也会对一定的结构产生一定的裂口
there's enough of a lip with enough structure...
因此宇航员也会被这样的裂口钩住手套
so that an astronaut could catch their glove on such a lip...
扯破手套
and cause a tear in their glove.
如果弹丸只有1/32英寸宽
And if a projectile only 1/32 of an inch wide...
就会产生这种伤害的话
can cause this type of damage...
你难道不认为更大的物体也是如此
you won't believe what a larger object can do.
在新墨西哥的航天局白沙测试基地里
At the NASA White Sands Test Facility in New Mexico...
研究人员将小弹丸装进了大炮里
researchers load small projectiles into huge guns.
这些弹丸用来模拟微流星体和太空垃圾
The projectiles simulate micrometeoroids and space junk.
它们以时速1.9万英里撞击航天飞机部件
They slam into spacecraft parts at up to 19,000 miles an hour...
在地球上制造灾难
creating disasters on Earth...
以更好地了解太空中的灾难
to better understand disasters in space.
在这种惊人的高速下
At such incredibly high speeds...
很小的物体都会造成极大的麻烦
a very small object can cause very big trouble.
我现在是在我们最大的
I'm standing inside of our largest target chamber...
一英寸大炮的靶室里
of our one-inch gun.
这炮有175英尺长
The gun is 175 feet long...
可以发射3/4英寸大小的弹丸
and can launch up to a 3/4-inch-sized projectile.
我手里拿的靶子
I'm holding a target...
是被5/8英寸的弹丸撞击的
that was impacted with a 5/8-inch projectile.
你可以看到 这是射入口
And as you can see, this is the entry hole...
它整个穿透了这个测试部件
and it went all the way through the test article.
这种规模的撞击在太空中是个灾难性的事件
An impact of this size would be a catastrophic event in space.
国际空间站的宇航员赖以生存的唯一指望
The only hope the International Space Station crew...
就是戴上紧急呼吸面罩
would have for survival is to put on emergency breathing masks...
进入返回舱
and head to the reentry capsule.
不足一英寸的物体就可以迫使他们放弃
An object less than an inch wide would have forced them to abandon...
这个价值数十亿美元的设施
this multi-billion-dollar facility.
那种情景就是为何宇航员去空间站外面
That type of scenario is the reason why...
要不断增加额外的保护层的
crews are constantly adding extra layers of protection...
原因所在
to the outside of the space station.
对于另一类空间碰撞 我们只能怪罪自己
For another type of space collision, we have only ourselves to blame.
1997年 一名俄罗斯宇航员
In 1997, a Russian cosmonaut...
遇上了一个险情 当时他在引导无人驾驶货运飞船
had trouble guiding an unmanned cargo craft...
与和平号空间站的对接
to its docking point with the Mir Space Station.
现在 我们知道在航空上
Now, we know in aviation...
七成的意外人为造成的
that 70 percent of the accidents are human-related.
因此 无需惊讶 你会认为
So it wouldn't surprise you to think...
人类同样是太空意外事故中的
that humans have also a big role in accidents...
主要因素
and mishaps in space.
和平号碰撞实际上是因为
The Mir collision actually was because...
有一名宇航员抱怨没有充分训练
a crew member complained that he wasn't trained enough...
进行对接
to do the rendezvous...
而地面控制人员则坚持 "不管怎样你都得进行"
and the ground control team said, "Well, you have to do it anyway."
撞击发生了
The hit occurred.
它造成了舱压泄漏
It caused a leak in the cabin pressure...
所以他们开始失去舱压
so now they started to lose cabin pressure.
于是空间站开始翻滚
And then the space station started to tumble.
就像是只台球
It was like pool balls.
一个撞击另一个 造成了位移
One hits another, it causes it to move.
因此即使是微不足道的事情
So even a minor thing...
不就是控制对接
just the control of a rendezvous and docking...
几乎可以造成灾难性的后果
could have almost catastrophic consequence.
不过发生在太空中的灾难
But the disasters that have happened in space...
相对升空和返回的灾难
still pale in comparison...
可谓是小巫见大巫了
to the disasters of getting into space and returning.
有一个说法开头50英里
There is a saying that the first 50 miles...
和最后50英里
and the last 50 miles...
是任何一次任务中最危险的部分
are the most dangerous part of any mission.
1986年挑战者号发射灾难
The 1986 Challenger launch disaster...
以及2003年哥伦比亚号返回的悲剧就是佐证
and the 2003 Columbia re-entry tragedy make that clear.
然而如果我们要走出太阳系
But if we're ever going to travel beyond our solar system...
我们就需要超越我们现在的火箭技术
we're going to need to move beyond our current rocket technology.
有一种可能性 既刺激又恐惧
One possibility that both thrills and terrifies...
就是所谓的反物质引擎
is known as an antimatter engine.
在巨大的粒子加速器里
Inside massive particle accelerators...
科学家已经创造出了微量的反物质
scientists have created minute amounts of antimatter...
构成它的原子
which is made of atoms...
所携带的电荷与正常的原子刚好相反
that have the opposite charges of normal atoms.
因而对于反物质来说
So with antimatter...
电子是正电荷 而质子是负电荷
the electrons are positive and the protons are negative.
一旦物质与反物质接触
When matter and antimatter come into contact...
它们会同归于尽
they annihilate each other...
释放出巨大的能量
releasing tremendous amounts of energy.
反物质引擎可以百分之百地
Antimatter engines have a 100 percent conversion rate...
将物质转换成能量
of matter into energy.
要知道 即使是原子弹
Realize that even an atomic bomb...
也只有1%的效率
is only one percent efficient.
原子弹中只有1%的物质
Only one percent of the mass of an atomic bomb...
转换成了能量
is converted to energy.
在反物质引擎中
In an antimatter engine...
我们几乎能将其全部的物质
we're talking about nearly 100 percent of the mass...
转换成能量
converted into energy.
这就是下一个世纪潜在的推进系统
It is, for the next century, the propulsion system of choice.
不过存在着一个问题
But there's a problem.
一茶匙反物质
A teaspoon of antimatter...
有可能送我们越过太阳系
might be able to propel us across the solar system...
但是同样那一茶匙
but that same teaspoon...
也具有摧毁整座城市的能量
also has the power to destroy an entire city.
一旦飞船进入深太空
And once a spacecraft is out in deep space...
简单的事故都会突然决定生与死
simple accidents can suddenly tip the balance from life to death.
随着我们闯入火星乃至更远
As we venture to Mars and beyond...
行程一次将会持续几年
with journeys lasting years at a time...
滞留太空所带来的风险
the chances of becoming stranded in space...
将会变得非常的大
will become much greater.
举个例子 在飞往火星途中
For example, on a flight to Mars...
要是有微流星体撞上氧气罐怎么办?
what if a micrometeoroid punches an oxygen tank?
要是你用完了呼吸用气又怎么办?
What if you just are simply running out of breathable air?
那你就束手无策了
There is nothing you can do.
你可以做的就是坐以待毙
You can die graciously is what you can do...
不管时间会有多长
however long it takes.
灾难的另一个源头
Another source of disasters...
尤其是在数年的漫长旅程中
especially with journeys measured in years...
就是好多人所忽视的情况
is something that many people overlook.
我们忘却的一个事情就是我们的同胞
One thing we forget is our fellow man...
我们的宇航员同胞
our fellow astronauts.
如果你关在小小的空间舱里
lf you're cooped up in this tiny, little space capsule...
可以这么说 用上一年功夫前往火星
for, let's say, a year at a time going to Mars...
或几年时间前往深太空 你会抓狂的
or years going into deep space, you can go crazy.
你会患上幽闭恐惧症
You can get claustrophobic.
隔壁的家伙已经搞得你神经兮兮
The guy next door could really get on your nerves...
你某种程度想掐死他
and you want to strangle him after a certain point.
尽管事故并没有广泛宣传
Although the incidents aren't highly publicized...
宇航员间的相处在过去就存在着问题
crew members have had problems getting along in the past...
结果相当危险
with dangerous results.
在1970年代 至少有一组苏联空间站的宇航员
There was at least one Soviet space station crew in the 1970s...
相处并不很融洽
that didn't get along pretty famously...
实际上据说发生了斗殴
and actually supposedly had a fistfight.
这些压力将会在这些长时间的
These stresses are going to manifest themselves...
任务中自我表现出来
on these long-duration missions.
大家都认为它们不就是在自欺欺人
Anybody who thinks they aren't is fooling himself.
为了让事情更加有趣
And to make things even more interesting...
俄国人据说在飞船上安排了枪支
Russian cosmonauts supposedly have firearms stowed onboard...
那是1965年偏离着陆点后 采取的一项预防措施
as a precaution after an extremely off-course landing in 1965.
宇航员降落在西伯利亚的森林里
The crew landed up in the woods in Siberia...
在那里呆了约三天时间
and were there for about three days...
他们不得不击退狼群 直到自己被营救
and they had to fight off wolves until they were rescued.
经过了那项特使的使命后 苏联决定
After that particular mission, the Soviets decided...
他们将在每一个联盟号太空舱里
that they were going to put a sawed-off shotgun...
配置短筒猎枪
in every Soyuz capsule...
以防类似的事情再次发生
in case something like that happened again.
现在据说宇航员都配有手枪
The cosmonauts are now rumored to have handguns...
存放在应急箱里
stored in emergency kits.
但是没有人急欲提供太空配枪的任何官方细节
But no one is eager to offer any official details of guns in space.
配载武器所带来的风险
And the risk of having a weapon aboard...
一旦情绪失控 就难说了
isn't just a concern if tempers flare.
实际上有一个实验任务专家的备案案例
There is actually a documented case...
他曾经搭载过航天飞机
of a payload specialist, who flew on a shuttle flight...
他们的实验失败了
whose experiment failed...
他毕生都在为这个实验做准备
and he spent his whole life getting this experiment ready...
实验失败后 他真的考虑过自杀
it failed, and he actually talked about killing himself.
组员们其实试图保护他
And the crew themselves actually tried to protect him...
守住舱口 这样他就没办法将他们杀死
and guarded the hatch so he wouldn't kill them.
纵然得到了迄今为止所有太空旅行的经验教训
Even with all of the space travel lessons learned so far...
有一点是明白无误的:
one thing is clear:
谁都无法阻止
nothing can completely prevent disasters...
将来所遭遇的灾难
from striking in the future.
如果我们要继续人类太空飞行
If we're going to continue human space flight...
我们就必须接受这种风险
we have to accept the risk...
因为这是个非常危险的活动
because it is a very dangerous occupation.
但是我们必须应对风险
But we have to manage the risk...
那将需要出色的技术人员
and that's going to require good technical people...
和出色的领导
and good leadership.
但是正如灾难不可避免一样
But just as surely as disasters will strike...
另外一点也是必然的
there is another certainty...
只要提及载人航天探索
when it comes to manned space exploration.
我认为我们有一个基因
I think we have a gene...
探索的基因
a gene for exploration...
发现的基因
a gene for discovery.
不仅仅是它有益于我们的进化
Not only is it good for our evolution...
因为我们找到了繁育和殖民的新途径
because we find new avenues to reproduce and to colonize...
同时我认为在我们人类的灵魂深处
but I think it's also inside the spirit of human beings...
就是想了解外面的世界
to want to know what's out there.
是否有可能到达我们以前从未涉足过的地方呢?
Is it possible to reach areas that we've never been before?
刺激...
And the thrill...
作为探索新大陆第一人的刺激
the thrill of being the first person to explore new terrain...
实在是妙不可言
is simply fantastic.